Guide to the Donald Bertrand Tresidder, President of Stanford University, Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Donald Bertrand Tresidder, president of Stanford University, papers
1918-1950
1942-1949
SC0151
Tresidder, Donald Bertrand, 1894-1948
20 Linear feet (40 boxes)
Office files of the President's Office during Tresidder's tenure as President, 1943-1948. Also included is some material from the earlier presidency of Dr. Ray Lyman Wilbur, who became Chancellor of the University in 1942.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
These records were received by the Stanford University Archives via administrative transfer from the Office of the President in 1968.
Information about Access
Files in Series 7 are restricted until January 1, 2025. Otherwise the records are open for research; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
A Stanford graduate (A.B. 1919, M.D. 1927), Donald Tresidder was President of the Curry Company of Yosemite Park (1925-1948), a member of the Stanford Board of Trustees and its President (1939-1942), and fourth President of Stanford University (1943-1948).
Description of the Collection
Office files of the President's Office during Tresidder's tenure as President, 1943-1948. Also included is material from the earlier presidency of Dr. Ray Lyman Wilbur, who became Chancellor of the University in 1942.
Arrangement note
The records are arranged in eight series: General Files; Departments; Military Programs; Funds; Scholarships and Fellowships; Disbanding of Sororities on Campus; Restricted Files; and Speeches.
Access Terms
Stanford University. Office of the President; Tresidder, Donald Bertrand, 1894-1948; Wilbur, Ray L., (Ray Lyman), 1875-1949; Military training.; Sororities.; World War, 1939-1945
Collection Contents
- General Files, Series 1
  - A, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Admission, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alumni Association, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Alumni Conference (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Alumni Deceased, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American Association of Junior Colleges, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American Association of University Professors, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - American Council on Education, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - American Red Cross, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Army - General, 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Associated Students, 1944-1947 (Box 1, Folder 11-13)
  - Association of American Colleges, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Athletics - General, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Audio-visual Committee, 1946-1949 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - B, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Belgian American Education Foundation, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Board of Athletic Control, 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Graduate School of Business, 1944-1948 (Box 2, Folder 7-12)
  - Business Manager, 1945-1948 (Box 3, Folder 1-4)
  - Business Manager - Stanford Properties, 1945-1948 (Box 3, Folder 5-7)
  - Butano Forest, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Compulsory Military Training, 1944-1947 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Contracts expired - Psychology (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Contracts expired - Engineering, 1943-1949 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Contracts expired - Medicine, 1942-1948 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Carmel - Stanford House, 1943-1945 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Controller, 1945-1949 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Council for Inter-American Cooperation, 1944-1945 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Dean of Men, 1944-1946 (Box 4, Folder 9-10)
  - Dean of Students, 1946-1948 (Box 5, Folder 1-3)
  - Dean of Women, 1944-1946 (Box 5, Folder 4-5)
  - Dental School, 1927-1943 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Deferments - General Correspondence, 1944-1945 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Deferments - under 26, 1944-1945 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Electron Optics, 1945-1946 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Financial - Vice-President (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Proposed Four-Year Program 1944- Fraternities, 1946-1947 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Functions, 1944-1947 (Box 6, Folder 2-4)
  - Food Research Institute, 1944-1947 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Gage Research Laboratory, 1945-1948 (Box 6, Folder 6-7)
  - Genera Secretary, 1944-1949 (Box 6, Folder 8-9)
  - Proposed Institute of Gerontology, 1946-1947 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - H, 1944-1945 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Health, School of, 1944-1946 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Health Service, 1946-1949 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Hopkins Marine Station, 1944-1948 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Hospital Finance Committee - Medical- School, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Housing - general, 1944-1945 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Housing, 1949-1950 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Housing and Feeding - Men, 1944-1945 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Housing and Feeding - Women, 1944-1945 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Humanities (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - I, 1944-1945 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Institute of Pacific Relations, 1944-1945 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Insurance - General, 1944-1945 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Insurance - Group Hospitalization, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Inter-governmental- Relations Committee, 1944-1945 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - International Survey Committee, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - J, 1944-1945 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - K, 1944-1945 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - L, 1944-1945 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Lagunita Knoll, 1944-1945 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Lane Library (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Law School, 1945-1949 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Law School Plan - Luncheon Lists, etc., 1945-1946 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Law School Plan - Gift Progress Reports, Acknowledgement of Gifts, etc., 1945-1946 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Law Schoo1 Plan - Drafts of letters, charts, etc., 1945-1946 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Law School Plan Booklet, 1945-1946 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Law School Plan, 1945-1946 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Law School Plan - General Correspondence, 1943-1946 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Leases (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Library, 1944-1948 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Library, 1944-1948 (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
  - Library - Hoover, 1944-1948 (Box 11, Folder 3-5)
  - Library - Hoover, 1944-1948 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Library Survey, 1946-1948 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Lower Division Honors, 1938-1942 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Henry R. Luce (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - M, 1944-1945 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Manuscripts, 1944-1945 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Medical School, 1944-1946 (Box 12, Folder 7-8)
  - Medical School - Appointments, Resignations, Leaves (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Medical School - Chandler discussions on fund raising, 1948 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Medical School - Navy V-L2 Program, 1945-1946 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Medical School - Nursing, 1945-1946 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Memorial Church and Religion, 1944-1947 (Box 13, Folder 5-6)
  - Men's Council, 1944-1946 (Box 13, Folder 7-8)
  - Men's Rest Home, 1944-1945 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Microwave Laboratory, 1943-1946 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1943-1947 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Music Listening Room, 1944-1945 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Natural History Museum, 1944-1947 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - N, 1944-1945 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - National Association of Manufacturers, 1944-1945 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - School of Naval Administration, 1945-1947 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Application and Preliminary Visit of N.R.O.T.C. Officials 1945 Jul 30-Aug 3 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - N.R.O.T.C. Contracts, 1945-1946 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Navy Programs, 1945-1947 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Newell - Litigation, 1928-1943 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - O, 1944-1945 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - P, 1944-1945 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Committee on Pacific and East Asian Studies, 1945-1949 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Pacific Coast Athletics Conference, 1946-1947 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Proposed Pacific Institure, 1944-1945 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Palo Alto Hospital, 1944-1945 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Passes, 1944-1945 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Pensions, 1919-1945 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - People Who Believe, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Director of Planning, 1946-1950 (Box 15, Folder 5-7)
  - Memoranda on Planning - Lewis Mumford, 1945-1946 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Planning Department - Housing - General, 1945-1946 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Planning Department - Housing - Interdale, 1946 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Planning Department - Housing - Row Apartments, 1946 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Planning Department - Law School Building, 1945-1946 (Box 15, Folder 12-13)
  - P1anning Department - Law Dormitory, 1945-1946 (Box 15, Folder 14-15)
  - Planning Department - Medical Building, 1945 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Planning Department - Physics Building, 1946 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Planning Department - Press, 1946 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Planning Department - Riding Stables, 1945 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Planning Office, 1945-1946 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Policies, 1944-1945 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Presidents Report, 1944-1945 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Press Articles, 1944-1945 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Professorships, 1944-1945 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Publicity, 1944-1945 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Publicity - Dr. Tresidder, 1944-1945 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Radio Station, 1946-1947 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Recommendation Letters, 1944-1949 (Box 16, Folder 8-11)
  - Registrar, 1945-1947 (Box 16, Folder 12-13)
  - R.O.T.C. - General, 1946-1948 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - S, 1947-1948 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Scholarships - General, 1944-1945 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Thomas A. Spragens, 1947-1948 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Staff - General, 1944-1948 (Box 17, Folder 2-3)
  - Stanford Associates, 1944-1948 (Box 17, Folder 4-5)
  - Stanford Associates - Exceptional Students, 1947-1948 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Stanford Association (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Stanford Athletic Council, 1946-1947 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Stanford Booklet, 1944-1945 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Stanford Daily, 1947 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Stanford Eye Bank, 1947 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Stanford Fund, 1944-1945 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Stanford Fund R-Plan, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Stanford Guidance Nursery School, 1945-1948 (Box 17, Folder 14-15)
  - Stanford Motion Picture, 1944-1945 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Stanford Pioneers, 1944-1945 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Stanford Research Institute, 1947-1948 (Box 17, Folder 18-19)
  - Stanford Speakers' Bureau, 1947-1948 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Today, 1947-1948 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Stanford Union, 1922-1934, 1944-1945, 1947-1948 (Box 18, Folder 3-6)
  - Students - General, 1944-1948 (Box 18, Folder 7-10)
  - Student Guide Service, 1945-1948 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Student Loan Fund, 1945-1946 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Student Publications, 1944-1945 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Surplus Property Materials, 1946-1947 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Surplus War Material, 1944 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - T, 1944-1945 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Time Educational Project, 1946-1949 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Donald B. Tresidder, 1944-1946 (Box 19, Folder 4-5)
  - Donald B. Tresidder - Trips, 1946 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Tresidder Administration - Speech by W.P. Fuller Jr. (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Tuition, 1944-1949 (Box 19, Folder 8-9)
  - U, 1944-1945 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Study of Stanford's Undergraduate Program (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - UNESCO, 1947-1948 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - United Nations Conference, 1945 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Universities (Various), 1944-1946 (Box 20, Folder 2-3)
  - University of California, 1944-1945 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - University of Chicago, 1944-1945 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - U.S. Department of the Interior - Fish and Wildlife Service, 1945 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - V, 1944-1945 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Vaccinations, 1939-1945 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - V-E Day, 1945 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Veterans, 1944-1945 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Veterans Education, 1944-1945 (Box 20, Folder 11-12)
  - Washington Office, 1944-1960 (Box 20, Folder 13-14)
  - Western College Congress Proposal, 1947 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Women's Council, 1944-1945 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Women's Rest Home, 1944-1945 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Yosemite Conference, 1947 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Association of American Universities, 1917-1947 (Box 21, Folder 5-8)
  - Association of American Universities, 1917-1947 (Box 22, Folder 1-7)
  - Board of Trustees, 1944-1946 (Box 22, Folder 8-9)
  - Academic Affairs Committee, 1943-1945 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - George A. Ditz - Trustee, 1945-1946 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Mrs. Roger Goodan - Trustee, 1945 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Herbert Hoover - Trustee, 1945 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Letters to the Board of Trustees, 1948-1949 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Trustees Manual, 1943-1944 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Questionnaire regarding development of regional membership, 1944-1945 (Box 23, Folder 2)
- Departments, Series 2
  - Art - Preliminary report, 1946 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Biology, 1944-1948 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Chemistry, 1944-1948 (Box 23, Folder 5-8)
  - Economics, 1944-1948 (Box 23, Folder 9-12)
  - English, 1944-1947 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Geology, 1944-1946 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Germanic Languages, 1944-1947 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - History, 1944-1947 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Mathematics, 1944-1949 (Box 24, Folder 5-7)
  - Music, 1940-1946 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Physics (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Political Science, 1944-1945 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Physical Education and Athletics, 1945-1946 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Physical Education - Women, 1945-1946 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Physical Therapy, 1946-1948 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Psychology, 1945-1947 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Romanic Languages, 1944-1947 (Box 25, Folder 7-8)
  - Social Sciences, 1944-1947 (Box 25, Folder 9-10)
  - Speech and Drama, 1944-1947 (Box 25, Folder 11-12)
  - Education, 1944-1947 (Box 25, Folder 13-14)
  - Education, 1944-1947 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Education - Appointments, resignations, leaves, 1946-1948 (Box 26, Folder 2-4)
  - Education - Dean, 1945-1946 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Engineering, 1944-1948 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - School of Engineering, 1944-1948 (Box 27, Folder 1-3)
  - Aeronautical Engineering, 1945-1948 (Box 27, Folder 4-5)
  - Civil Engineering, 1944-1948 (Box 27, Folder 6-9)
  - Electrical Engineering, 1944-1948 (Box 27, Folder 10-12)
  - Electrical Engineering, 1944-1948 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Electron Optics, 1944-1945 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Mechanical Engineering, 1944-1948 (Box 28, Folder 3-6)
  - Mining Engineering, 1944-1946 (Box 28, Folder 7-8)
- Military Programs, 1943-1946; Series 3
  - Army Specialized Training Program (A.S.T.P.) - S.T.A.R. - C.A.T.S., 1943-1944 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - A.S.T.P. - Curriculum (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - A.S.T.P. - Engineering (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - A.S.T.P. - E.R.C. (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - A.S.T.P. - Far Eastern Area and Language (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - A.S.T.P. - General (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - A.S.T.P. - Housing and Messing (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - A.S.T.P. - Medical and School of Health (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - A.S.T.P. - Tests (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - A.S.T.P. - Textbooks and Equipment (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - A.S.T.R.P. (R.0.T.C.) - General (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Civil Commnunications Intelligence School - Army Service forces (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - C.A.T.S. - General (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - C.A.T.S. - Contracts (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - C.A.T.S. - Housing and Messing (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - E.S.M.W.T. - General (Box 29, Folder 8-9)
  - W.A.C. - Physical Therapy (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - War Manpower Commission (Box 29, Folder 11)
- Funds, Series 4
  - Wallace McKinney Alexander and Timothy Leonard Barker Fund, 1944-1945 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Alumni Jordan Medical Fund, 1930-1945 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Mary D. Barber Trust Fund, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - George Davis Bivin Foundation, 1945 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Gordon Blanding Medical School Fund, 1944-1948 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Walter W. Boardman Memorial Fund, 1941-1946 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Cooperative Educational Fund, 1935-1940 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - The Bertha E. Dworzed Memorial Fund, 1944-1946 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - George E. Farrand Loan Fund, 1928-1945 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Eugene B. Favre Memorial Fund, 1940-1945 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Finnish Relief Fund, 1941-1947 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Foundation for American Citizenship, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - John Laurence Frost Loan Fund, 1935-1945 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Frost Infantile Paralysis Research, 1944-1949 (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - A.A. Gallenkamp Medical School Fund, 1937-1940 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - William Arnfield Holt and Ethel Rhodes Holt Fund, 1943-1947 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - George T. Keating Collection, 1944-1945 (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - W.K. Kellogg Foundation Medical Loan Fund, 1942-1944 (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - W.K. Kellogg Foundation Loan Fund for Physical Therapy Students, 1943-1944 (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - Joseph Horton Kile Endowment, 1942-1944 (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - Alice W. Kimball Loan Fund, 1928-1931 (Box 30, Folder 21)
  - Geraldine Kinne (anonymous), 1943-1946 (Box 30, Folder 22)
  - Knapp Fund, 1942-1943 (Box 30, Folder 23)
  - Lane Medical Library Book Fund, 1923-1943 (Box 30, Folder 24)
  - Law School - Library Endowment Fund, 1945-1947 (Box 30, Folder 25)
  - Eric Liljencrantz Memorial Section on Aviation Medicine, 1942-1947 (Box 30, Folder 26)
  - Medical Progress Fund, 1943 (Box 30, Folder 27)
  - Endowment for Medical Research, 1936-1941 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - The Memorial Fund at Stanford, 1940-1948 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Charles E. Merrill Fund, 1943-1949 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Louise Wiepking Meyer Loan Fund, 1942-1944 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Lydia Pearce Mitchell Fund, 1944 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Hans Christian Nelson Loan Fund, 1939-1940 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Funds - O (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Publications Fund - Graduate School of Business, 1945 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Edgar Rickard Gift - Hoover Library, 1946 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Robson Arthritis Fund, 1942-1944 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Schulte Endowment Research Fund in Pharmacology and Therapeutics, 1939-1944 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Flora Sharon Bequest, 1931-1948 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Shattinger Foundation, 1943-1944 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Jeannette Bell Shedd Memorial Fund, 1939-1948 (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Francis M. Shook Fund - Otolaryngology, 1947 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Leon Sloss Jr. Fund, 1944-1947 (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - M. C. Sloss Loan Fund, 1939-1944 (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - James Perrin Smith Library of Cephalopoda, 1935 (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Somers Memorial Research Fund, 1950 (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - Romaine Josephine Stanley Loan Fund, 1927-1948 (Box 31, Folder 20-21)
  - Sutherland, Tucker, and Bentley Trust Fund, 1927-1936 (Box 31, Folder 22)
  - U. S. Government Student War Loans, 1942 (Box 31, Folder 23)
  - Funds - V (Box 31, Folder 24)
  - Lilly, Eli and Company - Cheney "Experimental Ulcers", 1949 (Box 31, Folder 25)
  - Viking Fund - General, 1942-1943 (Box 31, Folder 26)
- Scholarships and Fellowships, Series 5
  - Abbott Laboratories Fellowship in Chemistry, 1945 (Box 31, Folder 27)
  - Academy of Time Fellowship, 1947 (Box 31, Folder 28)
  - The Adams Fellowship, 1948 (Box 31, Folder 29)
  - American Farm Bureau Federation, 1948 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Anheuser Busch Fellowship, 1941 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Anonymous for Departments of Engineering and Mathematics, 1945-1947 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Eliza Shaw Baker Scholarship Fund, 1949 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Harry L. Borders Scholarship, 1937-1947 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Briggs, Ella P. and Evelyn Fannie Scholarships, 1927-1942 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - C. Annette Buckel Foundation, 1913-1944 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Margaret Byrne Scholarship, 1931-1937 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Carnegie Corporation of New York Fellowship, 1941 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Chinese Scholarships, 1945-1948 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Class of (various years) Scholarships, 1934-1943 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Charles A. Coffin Fellowships, 1935-1946 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Colgate-Palmolive-Peet Co. Fellowships, 1935-1946 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Commercial Credit Co. Scholarships, 1940-1945 (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Consolidated Vultee Aircraft Corporation Scholarship, 1943-1949 (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Consolidated Vultee Aircraft Fellowship, 1946 (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - E. C. Converse Scholarship Fund, 1922 (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - George E. Crothers Scholarship in Law, 1918-1949 (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - Cutter Laboratories Fellowship, 1944 (Box 32, Folder 19)
  - Derby Seholarship, 1943-1944 (Box 32, Folder 20)
  - Mrs. Irene B. Dernham Scholarship - Medical School, 1947-1948 (Box 32, Folder 21)
  - W.F. Detert Scholarship in Engineering, 1944-1948 (Box 32, Folder 22)
  - Henry R. Dodds Scholarship, 1921-1951 (Box 32, Folder 23)
  - Dowrie Scholarship, 1945-1949 (Box 32, Folder 24)
  - Dunn Seholarship, 1923-1945 (Box 32, Folder 25)
  - Ethyl Gasoline Corporation Fellowship, 1942 (Box 32, Folder 26)
  - Field-Hotaling Scholarship and Fellowship Fund, 1937-1949 (Box 32, Folder 27)
  - Mary E. Fletcher Scholarships in Education, 1941-1948 (Box 32, Folder 28)
  - Elizabeth Gamble Fellowship, 1942 (Box 32, Folder 29)
  - Justitia Jane Campbell Glennie Scholarship, 1938 (Box 32, Folder 30)
  - William Haas Scholarship Fund, 1943-1944 (Box 32, Folder 31)
  - John M. Haffner Scholarship Fund, 1944-1945 (Box 32, Folder 32)
  - Carrie Hassler Endowment for Scholarships in the School of Medicine, 1934-1948 (Box 32, Folder 33)
  - James and Mildred Hollingsworth Fellowship, 1945 (Box 32, Folder 34)
  - Gladys E. Horner Scholarship Fund, 1938 (Box 32, Folder 35)
  - Albert Guerard Scholarship, 1946-1948 (Box 32, Folder 36)
  - Huntington Library Fellowship, 1947 (Box 32, Folder 37)
  - Imperial Oil Co. Graduate Research Fellowship, 1949 (Box 32, Folder 38)
  - Jergins Oil Fellowship in Micropaleontology, 1941 (Box 32, Folder 39)
  - W.K. Kellogg Foundation Medical Scholarship Fund, 1942-1945 (Box 32, Folder 40)
  - The Lederlie Laboratories Fellowship, 1945 (Box 32, Folder 41)
  - Ernest A. Love Memorial Scholarship, 1947-1948 (Box 32, Folder 42)
  - Master Brewers Association of America Protein Research Fellowship, 1943 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Medical School - Post-War Fellowship Fund, 1943-1946 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Merck and Company Fellowship, 1945 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Charles E. Merrill War Veterans Fund, 1946 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Dorothy Metz Scholarship, 1921-1943 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Frederick Dewey Michails Scholarship, 1939 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - National Canners Association Illuminiation Fellowship, 1948 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Henry Newell Scholarship Fund, 1922-1940 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Margaret Rogers Peterson Memorial Fund, 1945-1946 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Francis I. Proctor Memorial, 1945-1946 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Safeway Illumination Research Fellowship, 1940 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - San Francisco Panhellenic Fund, 1933-1944 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Seale Scholarships, 1932-1938 (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - The Senior Class Scholarship Fund, 1940-1943 (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - The Stanford Chapter of American Society of Civil Engineers Scholarship, 1925-1942 (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Stanford Club of San Jose, 1925-1941 (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - Leland Stanford Scholarship, 1936-1947 (Box 33, Folder 17)
  - Sterling-Winthrop Fellowship in Pharmacology, 1943-1949 (Box 33, Folder 18)
  - Lucie Stern Fellowship in Neurosurgery, 1938 (Box 33, Folder 19)
  - Lucie Stern Fellowship for Special Study, 1939 (Box 33, Folder 20)
  - Rosie Sternheim Memorial Scholarship Fund, 1948 (Box 33, Folder 21)
  - John Maxson Stillman Scholarship, 1927-1944 (Box 33, Folder 22)
  - James N. Stuart Fund, 1946 (Box 33, Folder 23)
  - Swift and Company Nutrition Fellowship, 1948 (Box 33, Folder 24)
  - Catherine Whalley Sykes Scholarship, 1944 (Box 33, Folder 25)
  - Tau Beta Pi Fellowship Award, 1946 (Box 33, Folder 26)
  - Tolman Scholarship Fund, 1938-1948 (Box 33, Folder 27)